A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 1-3254 FA739A
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Some problems related to establishment of better selection standards and procedures for foreign graduate students (Reports 003246), 1965; Fox, Melvin J. (Box 144)
  Summary prepared for presentation at the 79th annual convention of the National Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges. --p.1.
  Graduate students, Foreign -- United States; Student exchange programs -- United States; State universities and colleges -- United States; Universities and colleges -- United States -- Graduate work; Education (Graduate) -- United States; Education (Graduate)
- Organizations concerned with foreign students (Reports 003247), 1965; Fox, Melvin J. (Box 144)
  Students, Foreign -- United States; Student exchange programs -- United States; Education, Higher -- International cooperation
- Non-western studies in the undergraduate curriculum (Reports 003248), 1958; Elliott, David C. (Box 144)
  Education, Higher -- United States -- Curricula; Universities and colleges -- Curricula -- United States
- Improvement of international studies through a program of summer conferences, April 12-13-14 1956 (Reports 003249), Snyder, Richard C. (Richard Carlton), 1916-1976 (Box 144)
  International education -- United States -- Curricula; Foreign study -- United States; Education, Higher -- International cooperation; Northwestern University (Evanston, Ill.)
- The relationship of the Ford Foundation to the field of ETV and specifically to the National Educational Television Center (Reports 003250), 1964; Schmid, Robert C., 1916- (Box 144)
  Memo to James Armsey, dated December 4, 1964.
  Television in education -- United States; Educational television programs -- United States; Educational television stations -- United States; National Educational Television and Radio Center
- Notes on problems of the improvement of education for the advancement of human welfare (Reports 003251), 1953; Faust, Clarence H. (Clarence Henry), 1901-1975; Eurich, Alvin C. (Alvin Christian), 1902-1987 (Box 144)
  [52] p.
  Humanitarianism -- United States; Education -- United States; Educational equalization -- United States; Fund for the Advancement of Education (U.S.)
- Direct and indirect benefits to institutions of higher education in the United States resulting from grants by the Ford Foundation, January 1951-September 1952 (Reports 003252) (Box 144)
  2, 43 p.: principally tables: 28 cm.
  Universities and colleges -- United States -- Finance; Education, Higher -- United States -- Finance; Research grants -- United States; Scholarships -- United States
- Activities of the Ford foundation in South Asia and the Near and Far East (Reports 003253), 1952 (Box 144)
  Technical assistance -- South Asia; Technical assistance -- Middle East; Endowments -- South Asia -- Evaluation; Endowments -- Middle East -- Evaluation
- Projected Near East development program 1954-1956 (Reports 003254), 1953; Culbertson, Robert E. (Box 144)
  26 p. + attachment
  Charity organization -- Middle East; Endowments -- Near East; Philanthropy -- Near East
- Improving the Education of Primary Teachers in India (Report 000529), 1961 (Box 144)